Mark Andrews

123 Your Street, San Francisco, CA 12345 markandrews(o)exampLe.com (123) 456-7890

A Senior Writer with 10+ years of experience, specializing in copywriting, content strategy, team management, and editing. A strong history of crafting over 300+ compelling journalism articles and film reviews for industry-Leading publications. Expertise in identifying creative solutions to refine content quality and improve style guidelines.

Education

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) Journalism

University of San Francisco, San Francisco, CA September 2007 - May 2011

Key Skills

- Copywriti ng
- Journalism
- · Style Guidelines
- Content Development
- Team Management

Professional Experience

Senior Writer

CinemaCritics.com., San Francisco, CA | May 2016 - Present

- Write comprehensive reviews of over 200+ films for a leading movie review website with over 5M subscribers, conduct critical analysis of themes, acting, scores, and plot, and provide observations on the artistic success of films within the larger cinema canon
- Manage a team of editors, content writers, and film critics to deliver compelling reviews of vintage and current commercial films, television, and indie films
- Coordinate with creative teams to identify process improvement opportunities to enhance style guidelines and improve the quality of content

Writer

Bay Area News, San Francisco, CA I May 2011 - May 2016

- Edited, wrote, and proofread 150+ journalism articles for an online news publication with over 800K monthly subscribers, which included coordinating with journalists and staff writers to deliver compelling stories and opinion pieces on current events
- Evaluate articles prior to publication and deliver constructive criticism to writers to improve tone of voice and ensure proper handling of sensitive content matter